Finding Aid for Assistant to the President (University of Michigan) Records, 1913-1986
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Assistant to the President (University of Michigan) Records
1913-1986
University of Michigan. Assistant to the President.
861145 Bimu B6 2
Files concerning honorary degree recipients, University commencements, the Honors Convocations, and various University fellowships and scholarships; topical files of Frank E. Robbins, Erich Walter, Robert N. Cross, Herbert Hildebrandt, Richard L. Kennedy, William Cash, Jr., and James Shortt; and photographs
44 linear feet in 58 boxes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group (Donor No. 566 ) was transferred in several accessions beginning in 1966.
The records are open to research.
The office of Assistant to the President was created by President Burton in 1921 in conjunction with a reorganization of the Board of Regents committee structure. The Regents had operated with a series of subcommittees overseeing individual colleges or units. Burton persuaded the regents to focus on broader issues facing the university as a whole. The board reshaped itself with committees on the budget, on salaries, promotion of research, student welfare, educational policies, libraries, and buildings and grounds.
One result of the restructuring was that the deans, without a designated central committee to report to and work with, were forced to report their needs and plans directly to the president. Burton insisted on hiring an assistant to help with the increased workload. Frank R. Robbins, professor of Greek, was appointed to the post and served under four presidents through 1953.
The duties of assistant to the president covered a wide range of activities including membership on numerous university committees, overseeing many ceremonial affairs such as commencement, honors convocations, selection of honorary degree recipients.
With the appointment Erich Walter as Robbins' successor in 1953 the title was changed to Assistant to the President an Secretary of the University. In subsequent years the title and duties of the office have changed on several occasions. The duties of secretary of the university were split off as separate office and an Executive Assistant to President position was created.
Assistants to the President
1921-1953 Frank Robbins
1953-1966 Erich Walter
1966-1970 Herbert Hildebrandt
1970-1974 Richard L. Kennedy
1970-1983 William L. Cash, Jr.
1982-1988 James Shortt
Summary Contents List
Commencement and Honorary Degree Recipients
1925-1927, 1930-1965 -- [boxes 1-8, 31]
1965 Spring-1985 Winter (boxes 42-44, 51, 53-54]
University Committees
1933-1982 -- [boxes 36-37, 49]
Gift Acknowledgments
1973/74-1980/81 -- [boxes 13-17]
Henry Russel Lectureship
1953-1964 -- [box 33]
1964/65-1977/78 -- [boxes 44, 45]
1978/79-1985/86 -- [box 55]
Honors Convocations
1922-1966 -- [box 9]
1960-1973 -- [box 52]
1974-1985 -- [boxes 54-55]
Outstanding Teaching and Achievement Awards
1955-1964 -- [boxes 31, 33]
1964-1979 -- [boxes 45, 46, 52, 55]
1974-1979 -- [box 55)
Photographs -- [box 56]
Scholarships and Fellowships
General, 1966-1973 -- [boxes 10-13, 41]
Harrison, Seth, Scholarship, 1913-1968 -- [box 13]
Kennedy, Charles S., Scholarship, 1953-1957 -- [box 31]
Michigan Alumni Fund Scholarship, 1954/55 -- [box 32]
Rhodes Scholarship, 1963-1971 -- [box 45]
State of the University Addresses
1967-1979 -- [boxes 47-48]
1980-1985 -- [box 55]
Topical Files
General, 1933-1986 -- [boxes 30-34, 48-49, 53]
Topical Files of Cross, Robert N. (Administrative Assistant), 1949-1961 -- [boxes 34-36]
Topical Files of Erich Walter, 1945-1970 (includes some files of Herbert W. Hildebrandt -- [boxes 57-58]
Topical Files of Kennedy, Richard L., and Cash, William L., 1949-1983 -- [boxes 38-42]
Boxes 18-29, 47, and 50 were eliminated during 1992 reprocessing.
The Assistant to the President records contain file related to university commencements (1930-1965), honors convocations (1922-1966), the sesquicentennial celebration of the founding of the university in 1817, university fellowships, gifts, and prizes; correspondence and biographical sketches related honorary degree recipients, and State of the University Addresses. Also included are minutes of the meetings of the university's executive officers (1968-1982), dean's conferences (1951-1985), presidents' conferences (1965-1968), and topical files generated by the office (1933-1980). These records were generated during the tenures of Frank Robbins, 1921-1953; Erich Walter, 1953-1966; Herbert Hildebrand, 1966-1970; Richard Kennedy, 1970-1974; and William Cash, 1970-1983.
Subjects:
Cash, William Levi, 1915-; Kennedy, Richard L.; Shortt, James.; Students for a Democratic Society (U.S.); University of Michigan--Administration.; University of Michigan. Assistant to the President.; University of Michigan--Anniversaries, etc.; University of Michigan--Awards.; University of Michigan--Commencements.; University of Michigan--Gifts and loans.; University of Michigan--Degrees.; University of Michigan. Honors Convocation.; University of Michigan. Men's Glee Club.; University of Michigan--Students.; University of Michigan. President.; University of Michigan--Students--Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; University of Michigan. t State of the university address.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1961-1970.; Voice Political Party.; Minority college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Henry Russel Award (University of Michigan); Inglis House (University of Michigan); Outstanding Achievement Award (University of Michigan); Romance Languages Building (University of Michigan); University of Michigan. Assistant to the President.; University of Michigan--Buildings.; University of Michigan--Campus.; University of Michigan--Commencements.; University of Michigan. Honors Convocation.; University of Michigan. State of the University address.; Walter, Erich Albert.
Contributors:
Cross, Robert N.; Hildebrandt, Herbert W.; Robbins, Frank Egleston, 1884-; Walter, Erich Albert.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Honorary Degree Recipients
  [files relating to honorary degrees, 1921-1925 in M.L. Burton papers; honorary degrees, 1926-1929 are in C.C. Little papers]
  - 1925-1927 (Box 1)
    (miscellaneous)
  - 1930-1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941-1952 (Box 2)
  - 1953-1956 (Box 3)
  - 1957-1960 (Box 4)
  - 1960-1963 (Box 5)
  - 1963-1965 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - 1965-1966 (Box 42)
  - 1967-1971 (Box 43)
  - 1972-1976 (Box 44)
- Commencement
  - 1930-1957 (Box 7)
  - 1958-1965 (Box 8)
  - Addresses 1946, 1955, 1964 (Clinton Anderson, Earl Warren, and Lyndon Johnson), 1946-1964 (Box 8)
  - 1965 Spring-1973 Winter, 25 folders (Box 51)
    (includes list)
  - 1974 Spring-1977 Winter, 12 folders (Box 53)
  - 1978 Spring-1985 Winter, 22 folders (Box 54)
- Honors Convocation
  - 1922-1959 (Box 9)
  - Addresses, 1961-1966 (Box 9)
  - 1960-1973, 14 folders (Box 52)
- Scholarships and Fellowships
  - General
    - 1966/67-1967/68 (Box 10)
    - 1967/68 (cont.)- 1969/70, 1967-1970 (Box 11)
    - 1969/70 (cont.)- 1971/72, 1969-1972 (Box 12)
    - 1971/72 (cont.)- 1972/73, 1971-1973 (Box 13)
  - Seth Harrison Scholarship, 1913-1968 (Box 13)
  - List of all scholarships awarded through, 1938/39 (Box 13)
  - List of all fellowships awarded through, 1938/39 (Box 13)
- Gift Acknowledgments (includes foundation grants)
  - 1973/74 (Box 13)
  - 1973/74 (cont.)- 1974/75, 1973-1975 (Box 14)
  - 1975/76-1976/77 (Box 15)
  - 1976/77 (cont.)- 1978/79, 1976-1979 (Box 16)
  - 1978/79 (cont.)- 1980/81, 1978-1981 (Box 17)
- Topical Files--General, 1933-1980
  - Adams, F.P., 1951; 1959 (Box 30)
  - American Red Cross, 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Angell biography, 1954-1955 (Box 30)
  - Asia Foundation for Oriental Men, 1955-1959 (Box 30)
  - Assistants to the President, 1959-1960 (Box 30)
  - Barbour Scholarship Committee, 1955-1972 (Box 30)
  - Blind Students, 1964 (Box 30)
  - Board in Control of Student Publications, 1933 (Box 30)
  - Brandstrom, William J., 1956-1969 (Box 30)
  - Centennial of Women at the University, 1957 (Box 30)
  - Challenge, 1960-1967 (Box 30)
  - Chicago Tribune, Rating of the universities (Box 30)
  - 1957 (Box 30)
  - Citizens Advisory Committee on Hospitals, 1967-1968 (Box 30)
  - Class of Award, 1919; 1949-1955; 3 folders (Box 30)
  - Class of 1923 Literary Memorial Fund, 1954-1960 (Box 31)
  - Committee on Ceremonials, 1966-1967 (Box 31)
  - Conference on the University, 1964 (Box 31)
  - Conference on Student Life and Education, 1954-1955 (Box 31)
  - Dearborn Center, 1957-1959 (Box 31)
  - Dey, Surrenda Kumar, 1964-1966 (Box 31)
  - Distinguished Faculty Achievement Award, 1955-1963 (Box 31)
    (see also Box 46)
  - Distinguished Service Awards for Instructors and Assistant Professors, 1960-1963 (Box 31)
  - Donors, 1938 (Box 31)
  - Druids, 1958-1959 (Box 31)
  - English Language Institute, 1953-1959 (Box 31)
  - Flint College, 1955-1957 (Box 31)
  - Graduate School Convocation, 1958-1961 (Box 31)
  - Hart Fund, Carrye and Abraham S., 1962 (Box 31)
  - Hastings, Walter (Box 31)
  - Hatcher, Harlan, 1955-1963 (Box 31)
  - Heidelburg Team, 1954 (Box 31)
  - Higher Education in Michigan, 1955-1961 (Box 31)
  - Historical Society of Michigan, 1964 (Box 31)
  - Hobbs Airfield, ,1968, 1954-1955 (Box 31)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1955-1956; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Hopwood Committee, 1948-1953 (Box 31)
  - International Center, 1953-1972; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - International Congress of orientalists, 1964-1967 (Box 31)
  - Kennedy, Charles S., Scholarship, 1953-1957 (Box 31)
  - Lemeh, Charles, 1967 (Box 31)
  - Maxwell, Howard B., 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - Michigan Alumni Fund Scholarships and Tuition (Box 32)
  - Equalization, 1954-1955 (Box 32)
  - Michigan Quarterly Review, 1961-1970 (Box 32)
  - Michigan Union, 1958-1971 (Box 32)
  - Michigan Week, 1967-1970 (Box 32)
  - Mott Foundation Lectures, 1953-1957; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - National Consultative Conference on Religion and the State University, 1958; 8 folders (Box 32)
  - Nu Sigma Nu, 1966 (Box 33)
  - Orange Nassau Dinner, 1959 (Box 33)
  - Outstanding Achievement Award, 1958-1964; 6 folders (Box 33)
    (see also Box 45)
  - Peace Corps Plaque Dedication, 1964-1966 (Box 33)
  - Power Center Dedication, 1971 (Box 33)
  - President's Annual Staff Meeting, 1956-1966; 2 folders (Box 33)
  - President's Conference, 1966-1968 (Box 33)
  - Romance Language Building (old Museum Building), gargoyles (Box 33)
  - Russel, Henry, Lectureship, 1953-1964; 2 folders (Box 33)
    (see also Boxes 44-45)
  - Scott, Oreon E., Awards, 1952-1959; 8 folders (Box 33)
  - Soo Locks Centennial Celebration, 1952-1956; 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Student Government Council, 1963-1964 (Box 34)
  - Student Problems, 1967-1969 (Box 34)
  - Turner, Scott, 1962 (Box 34)
  - Tutorial and Cultural Relations Project, 1970 (Box 34)
  - University Flag, Mace and Seal, 1939-1980; 3 folders (Box 34)
  - University Press
    - Executive Committee, 1954-1955 (Box 34)
    - General, 1953-1965; 11 folders (Box 34)
  - Voice-Students for a Democratic Society, 1965-1966 (Box 34)
- Topical Files of Cross, Robert K. (Administrative Assistant), 1949-1965
  - Abelman, Frank, 1958 (Box 34)
  - Agriculture, 1956 (Box 34)
  - Alumni Association, 1958-1960 (Box 34)
  - Anatomical Material, 1958 (Box 34)
  - Appropriation: Comparisons, 1956-1960; 5 folders (Box 34)
  - Athletics, 1953-1955 (Box 34)
  - B (miscellaneous) (Box 35)
  - Biological Sciences (space needed), 1956-1957 (Box 35)
  - Broadcasting Service, 1952/53 (Box 35)
  - Buildings, UM, 1953-1955 (Box 35)
  - Bureau of Business Research, 1951-1957 (Box 35)
  - Business Administration, School of, 1945; 1955 (Box 35)
  - C (miscellaneous) (Box 35)
  - Capital Airlines, 1953-1954 (Box 35)
  - Carey, William J., 1953 (Box 35)
  - Civilian Defense, 1957 (Box 35)
  - Commercial Type Business School, 1960 (Box 35)
  - Community Colleges, 1956 (Box 35)
  - Conlin, Rollo G., 1953-1955 (Box 35)
  - Conlin Proposal, 1952-1953 (Box 35)
  - Cross, R.N. (personal), 1953-1956 (Box 35)
  - D (miscellaneous) (Box 35)
  - Dearborn Center, 1957-1959 (Box 35)
  - Dentistry, School of, 1954-1955 (Box 35)
  - Development Council, 1952-1956 (Box 35)
  - Directories, Faculty and Staff, 1960/61 (Box 35)
  - Donahue, Dr. Wilma, 1954-1955 (Box 35)
  - Education, School of, 1955 (Box 35)
  - Engineering, College of, 1953-1955 (Box 35)
  - Enrollment, 1953-1959; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - F (miscellaneous) (Box 35)
  - Faculty, 1951-1955 (Box 35)
  - Faculty Salary Reports, 1950-1956; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Flint Extension, 1954-1956 (Box 35)
  - Fluid Engineering Building, 1956 (Box 35)
  - Football, 1958-1961; 5 folders (Box 35)
  - Foundations, 1953-1955 (Box 36)
  - G (miscellaneous) (Box 36)
  - Girlstown, 1954-1957 (Box 36)
  - Great Lakes Commission, 1956 (Box 36)
  - Great Lakes Fishery Commission, 1956-1958 (Box 36)
  - Great Lakes Institute, 1954-1956 (Box 36)
  - Great Lakes Research Institute, 1955-1958 (Box 36)
  - Great Lakes State Industrial Development Council, 1957-1959 (Box 36)
  - H (miscellaneous) (Box 36)
  - Hatcher, Harlan, 1955 (Box 36)
  - Heating Plant and Utilities Extension, 1957 (Box 36)
  - Higher Education, 1953-1955; 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Highway Laboratory, 1955-1956 (Box 36)
  - Hospitals, 1952-1955; 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Howell, T.B. Sanatorium, 1955 (Box 36)
  - Industrial Development, 1951-1952 (Box 36)
  - I-L (miscellaneous) (Box 36)
  - Institute for Labor and Industrial Relations, 1957-1958 (Box 36)
  - Law School, 1953 (Box 36)
  - Legislative Tax Study Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 36)
  - Legislature, 1964-1965 (Box 36)
  - Libraries, 1949-1957 (Box 36)
  - M (miscellaneous) (Box 36)
  - Medical Center, 1955-1959; 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Medical Health, 1953-1955 (Box 36)
  - Medical Research (Federal Aid), 1955 (Box 36)
  - Medical School, 1955-1961; 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Medical Science Building, 1956-1958; 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Medical Society, 1959 (Box 36)
  - Michigan Department of Economic Development, 1954-1956 (Box 36)
  - Michigan Education Association, 1953-1955 (Box 36)
  - Michigan Retail Hardware Association, 1953-1954 (Box 36)
  - State Finances, 1952-1953 (Box 36)
- University Committees, 1933-1982
  - Academic Affairs Advisory Committee (SACUA (Box 36)
  - Committee), 1948-1980 (Box 36)
  - Adult Education Advisory Committee, 1957-1974 (Box 36)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1933-1979 (Box 36)
  - Biological Sciences, Division of, 1947-1967 (Box 36)
  - Biological Station, Executive Committee, 1940-1978 (Box 36)
  - Board of Admissions, 1951-1977 (Box 36)
  - Bylaws Committee (SACUA Committee), 1966-1978 (Box 37)
  - Career Planning and Placement, 1973-1978 (Box 37)
  - Committee on College Relations (SACUA Committee), 1950-1961 (Box 37)
  - Community Fund (United Way), 1935-1979 (Box 37)
  - Distinguished Faculty Achievement Awards, Committee on (SACUA Committee), 1956-1977 (Box 37)
  - Distinguished Service Awards for Instructors and Assistant Professors (SACUA Committee), 1960-1975 (Box 37)
  - Economic Development, Center for Research on, 1961-1980 (Box 37)
  - Economic Status of the Faculty (SACUA (Box 37)
  - Committee), Committee on the, 1966-1980 (Box 37)
  - Environmental Quality, Institute for, Faculty Advisory Committee (SACUA Committee), 1971-1975 (Box 37)
  - Financial Affairs, Committee on (SACUA Committee), 1971-1980 (Box 37)
  - Foreign Student Scholarships, Committee on, 1950-1971 (Box 37)
  - Freer Fund, Committee on the, 1946-1978 (Box 37)
  - Fresh Air Camp, 1956 (Box 37)
  - Health Insurance Program (student committee), 1956 (Box 37)
  - Health Sciences, Division of, 1935-1978 (Box 37)
  - Heart and Circulation and Related Disorders, Center for Research in Diseases of, Board of Scientific Directors, 1962-1978 (Box 37)
  - Hopwood Prize Fund (Avery and Julie), Committee on, 1930-1982 (Box 37)
  - Hospital Administration, Bureau of, Advisory Committee, 1958-1979 (Box 37)
  - Industrial Relations, Advisory Committee of the Bureau of, 1936-1969 (Box 37)
  - International Business, Program in, Executive Committee, 1961-1972 (Box 37)
  - International Center, Board of Governors, 1942-1971 (Box 37)
  - Japanese Studies, Center for, Executive Committee, 1947-1972 (Box 37)
  - Kresge Hearing Research Institute, 1960 (Box 37)
  - Lands Used for Instruction and Research, Committee on, 1930-1978 (Box 37)
  - Latin-American Scholarship Committee, 1955-1971 (Box 37)
  - Lecture Committee, 1950-1961 (Box 37)
  - Medical Center, Board in Control of, 1947-1974 (Box 37)
  - Mental Retardation and Related Disabilities, Institute for the Study of, Policy Committee, 1966-1977 (Box 37)
  - Michigan Union, Board of Directors, 1929-1979 (Box 37)
  - Orientation Committee, 1935-1973 (Box 37)
  - Patronesses, Board of, 1950-1968 (Box 37)
  - Phi Sigma Award, 1941-1972 (Box 37)
  - Professional Theatre Program, University Committee on, 1965-1976 (Box 37)
  - Public Health Economics, Bureau of, Advisory Committee, 1960-1971 (Box 37)
  - Radiation Policy Committee, 1950-1982 (Box 37)
  - Religious Affairs, Committee on, 1937-1978 (Box 37)
  - Resource Allocation, Committee on, 1970-1971 (Box 37)
  - Research Club, 1934-1977 (Box 37)
  - Research Policies Committee (SACUA Committee), 1968-1980 (Box 37)
  - Safety Committee, University, 1958-1977 (Box 37)
  - School Services, Bureau of, 1948-1970 (Box 37)
  - Senate Advisory Committees, miscellaneous subcommittees, 1952-1980 (Box 37)
  - Speech Improvement Camp, Advisory Committee, 1949-1970 (Box 37)
  - Standards and Conduct, University Committee on, 1934-1968 (Box 37)
  - Staff Benefits, Advisory Committee to the office of, 1934-1978 (Box 37)
  - State Relations Committee (SACUA Committee), 1975-1980 (Box 37)
  - Statistical Research Laboratory Executive Committee, 1946-1968 (Box 37)
  - Student Relations (SACUA Committee), 1964-1980 (Box 37)
  - Teacher Education and Certification, Joint Committee on, 1938-1978 (Box 37)
  - Tenure Committee (SACUA Committee), 1966-1980 (Box 37)
  - University Relations Committee (SACUA Committee), 1949-1980 (Box 37)
  - University Scholarships, Committee on, 1947-1969 (Box 37)
  - Vandenberg Lectureship Committee, 1967-1977 (Box 37)
  - Veteran's Hospital, Dean's Committee, 1948-1977 (Box 37)
  - Willow Run Laboratories, 1958-1960 (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous Files (Box 49)
- Topical Files of Kennedy, Richard L., and Cash, William L., 1949-1983
  - Academic Administrative Internship Program, 1974 (Box 38)
  - Academic Advisory Committee (Black Students), 1963-1971 (Box 38)
  - Advisory Committee on Recreation, Intramurals and Club Sports, 1972-1974 (Box 38)
  - Affirmative Action Office Review Committee, 1978 (Box 38)
  - Affirmative Action Program
    - 1949-1972 (Box 38)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 38)
  - American Indian, 1971-1972 (Box 38)
  - Battles, Ron, 1967-1976 (Box 38)
  - Bentley, Mrs. Alvin M., 1970-1971 (Box 38)
  - Black Action Movement, 1969-1975 (Box 38)
  - Black Students, 1969-1983 (Box 38)
  - Black Student Union, 1969-1971 (Box 38)
  - Black Studies Program, 1969-1978 (Box 38)
  - Center for Afro-American and African Studies, 1970-1976 (Box 38)
  - Child Care Action Center, 1971-1974 (Box 38)
  - Civil Liberties Board, 1978-1983 (Box 38)
  - Coalition for the Use of Learning Skills (CULS), 1970-1977 (Box 39)
  - Commission for Women, 1970-1974 (Box 39)
  - Commission on the Role of the Students in Decision-making, Report, 1966-1968 (Box 39)
  - Committee on Artifacts, 1962-1970 (Box 39)
  - Compliance Reports
    - 1967-1969 (Box 39)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 39)
    - 1972-1980 (Box 39)
  - Daane, R.K., 1971-1973 (Box 39)
  - Employment Services, 1969-1970 (Box 39)
  - Environmental Action for Survival (ENACT), 1970-1973 (Box 39)
  - Fleming, R.W.
    - 1969-1974 (Box 39)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 39)
    - 1974-1981 (Box 39)
  - Flint College, 1969-1974 (Box 40)
  - General Motors, 1970-1971 (Box 40)
  - Glee Club, 1970-1974 (Box 40)
  - Goodall, Leonard, 1968-1974 (Box 40)
  - Graduate Assembly, 1970-1971 (Box 40)
  - Graduate School, 1972-1978 (Box 40)
  - Greene Report, 1966-1967 (Box 40)
  - Handicapped, 1971-1976 (Box 40)
  - Housing Office, 1970-1972 (Box 40)
  - Human Relations
    - Advisory Council, 1968-1970 (Box 40)
    - Commission (Ann Arbor), 1969 (Box 40)
    - Coordinating Committee, 1968-1971 (Box 40)
    - General, 1968 (Box 40)
  - Johnson, Henry, 1971-1975 (Box 40)
  - Law School, 1968-1973 (Box 40)
  - Legislators and Congressmen, 1971 (Box 40)
  - Literature, Science and the Arts, College of, 1967-1975 (Box 40)
  - Medical School, 1969-1974 (Box 40)
  - Michigan Daily, 1972 (Box 40)
  - Minority Concerns, Council for, 1980-1982 (Box 40)
  - Minority Conferences, Big Ten Universities, 1974 (Box 40)
  - Minority Groups
    - Commission on, 1970-1974 (Box 40)
    - Data, 1968-1971 (Box 40)
    - Data Collection History, 1968-1976 (Box 40)
    - General, 1969-1971 (Box 40)
    - Law School, 1974-1975 (Box 41)
    - Programs, 1970-1971 (Box 41)
    - Recruitment, 1967-1970 (Box 41)
    - Task Force on Minority Supportive Services, 1971 (Box 41)
  - Minority Information
    - 1967-1969 (Box 41)
    - 1969-1973 (Box 41)
  - Open Meeting Bill, 1977 (Box 41)
  - Opportunity Program, 1974 (Box 41)
  - Optometry, Proposed School of (Box 41)
  - Overberger, Charles, 1972-1974 (Box 41)
  - Personnel Policies, 1969-1976 (Box 41)
  - Pierpont, Wilbur K., 1969-1973 (Box 41)
  - Power Center
    - General, 1970-1973 (Box 41)
    - Scheduling, 1972-1973 (Box 41)
  - Proposals, 1969-1970 (Box 41)
  - Public Health, School of, 1968-1974 (Box 41)
  - Recruitment and Placement Offices, 1968-1971 (Box 41)
  - Reed Report, 1962 (Box 41)
  - Research (Classified), 1971-1972 (Box 41)
  - Residential College, 1967-1972 (Box 41)
  - Richter, John A., 1973 (Box 41)
  - Rights of Privacy and Access to Information, 1976 (Box 41)
  - Scholarships and Fellowships, 1967-1973 (Box 41)
  - Special Projects
    - 1969 (Box 41)
    - 1969-1972 (Box 41)
  - Student Government Council, 1972-1974 (Box 41)
  - Third World Coalition, 1975 (Box 41)
  - Trotter House, 1972-1980 (Box 41)
  - University
    - Activity Center, 1973-1974 (Box 42)
    - Council, 1970-1982 (Box 42)
    - Facilities, Use of, 1971-1974 (Box 42)
    - Senate
      - 1960-1969 (Box 42)
      - 1971-1974 (Box 42)
  - University of Michigan-Detroit Public School Liaison Committee, 1968-1975 (Box 42)
  - Varner, Nellie, 1969-1975 (Box 42)
  - Warner, Robert, 1971-1974 (Box 42)
  - Washington Intern Program, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Women Intercollegiate Athletics, 1973-1974 (Box 42)
- Scholarships, Lectureships and Awards
  - Henry Russel Lectureship
    - 1964/65-1975/76 (Box 44)
  - Henry Russel Award (Box 45)
    - 1964/65-1975/76 (Box 45)
    - Background Materials (Box 45)
  - Rhodes Scholarship, 1963-1971 (Box 45)
  - Outstanding Undergraduate Teaching Award, 1967-1969 (Box 45)
  - Faculty Award Nominations, 1964-1977 (Box 46)
  - Junior Henry Russel Award, 1979 (Box 46)
- State of the University Addresses
  - 1967-1975 (Box 46)
  - 1976-1979 (Box 48)
  - 1980-1985, 6 folders (Box 55)
- Invitations/Greetings to other universities upon presidential inaugurations
  - Invitations (Box 48)
- Reports, background materials, etc.
  - Opportunity Awards Program, 1969 (Box 48)
  - Final Presentation on the Development of a Uniform Salary Program for Professional and Administrative Employees, 1972 (Box 48)
  - Appendices to Final Report on the Development of a Uniform Salary...., 1972 (Box 48)
  - Attitude and opinion Study: Freshmen Women's Hours and Visitation Policies, 1968-1969 (Box 48)
  - The University of Michigan Project Community Proposed Program and Budget, 1972-1973 (Box 48)
  - Report of the Special Study Committee for the Office of Student Affairs, 1962 (Box 48)